Hello everyone in this video
We are going to solve the problem move Zeroes.
So the problem description says that given an array nums write a
function to move all zeros to the end of it while maintaining
the relative order of non-zero elements.
So we can see the example.
In this example,
the first non-zero element is 1 which appears at the first position in the
output then the next element which is non zero is 3 so
it appears that the second position and the third non-zero
element is 12.
So it is appearing at the third position and rest are zeros.
You must do this in place without making a copy of
the array.
So we are not going to use auxiliary space here.
And we have to minimize the total number of operations.
So I will try to do this problem with 2 pointer approach.
In this I will keep 2 pointers i and
j respectively so I will use j to
Traverse the array while I will keep i so
that I can override at the i th position.
So let me try to explain this with the example.
With j
I'm going to traverse the array and as soon as I come up to an
element
which is non zero,
I will
Override the ith position with that particular element.
So let's say I'm moving from the start and the first non-zero
element is 3,  so I reach here.
Now I will overwrite i with
3 and then increment i
Then the next element which is non-zero is 6.
I will uh j will reach here and then I will override this.
and increment i
then I will come up to this.
This is zero again.
I will move to the next element.
So this is again a non-zero element.
So I will override i with this and
then increment i
Then I will come to 5
Again I will do this operation and increment i
then this again zero,
so nothing will happen.
And this is a non zero element.
So I will overwrite it.
Now I will reach here.
And j exits the loop.
Now the rest of the elements from i till the
end of the array, these are supposed to be zero so I
will make them zero.
So we are able to do this problem in big O for N time and
using constant extra space.
Now let us look at the code.
So I'm keeping i and j initially both are zero till
the time j is is smaller than nums .size().
if j comes to a non-zero element,
then simply overwrite i and increment i
and each time we have to increment j, this part of the code
this is actually this is actually this
1 we are making all the elements zero.
Starting from i so while i
is smaller than nums.size()
I will make all the elements till the end zero.
So this is it for the problem.
Thank you.